Andrew Kostyuk

Moscow, Russia

andrew.kostyuk@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/ankostyuk/en

github.com/ankostyuk

Have 10+ years experience of commercial development. Know the full cycle of software development from requirements analysis and design to task description to programmers, development and release of the product. Have a strategic vision of the product and an attention to details. I'm looking for interesting projects with open positions of full stack developer, teamlead, development manager.

Technical Skills

Development: Team and development management, Requirements analysis, Designing systems, UI, UX, SOA, OOP, TDD, Refactoring.

Programming languages: JavaScript, Java, Python.

Frontend: AngularJS, jQuery, Lodash, Raphaël, RequireJS, HTML, CSS, LESS, Bootstrap, Adobe Photoshop.

Backend: Spring Framework, Apache Tomcat, Node.js, Express, PhantomJS, Grunt.

Web: HTTP, REST, SOAP.

Data storage: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Neo4j, Apache Solr.

Testing: Unit testing, Integration testing, Alpha/Beta testing, Mock, Mocha, Chai, JMeter.

VCS: Git, Mercurial.

Bug tracking: Redmine, GitHub, Jira.

OS: Mac OS X, Linux, bash.

Experience

Lead Developer

Self-employed

November 2015 - Present

Guide implemented projects for National Credit Bureau Economic Security Service. Design and develop software. Analyse business requirements and work out specifications

Designed the support of Self-employed information and developed frontend.

Developed the algorithm for determining the historical connections based on the nondistinct data to support the history of relationships between companies and individuals for Unisearch and The Analysis Of Affiliated Persons And Final Beneficiaries, developed frontend.

Designed service of "Search For Signs Of Conflict Of Interest" – multi-faceted verification of relationships between companies lists and individuals, developed frontend.

Designed and developed public API of companies and individuals relationships for the National Credit Bureau Economic Security Service.

Technologies: JavaScript, AngularJS, RequireJS, jQuery, Lodash, HTML, CSS, LESS, Bootstrap, HTTP, REST, Node.js, Express, PhantomJS, Grunt, Java, Spring Framework, Apache Solr, Apache Tomcat, MongoDB, Neo4j.

Managed the development and release of the National Credit Bureau products, held technical interviews.

Lead Developer, CEO, Co-founder

[nullpointer]

July 2012 - November 2015

Outsourcing company. Moscow, Russia. null-pointer.ru

Founded a company, specializing on software development. Arranged business relations with clients, planned a budget and managed progects. Designed and developed software. Analysed business requirements and worked out specifications. Formed a software development team, held technical interviews. Led software development team, consisting of 2-7 members.

Our team executed following projects...

- * New products of National Credit Bureau Economic Security Service:
 - Unisearch. Search of the companies and individuals by the names, TIN, main state registration number, address, phone number. By means of this search
 you get the detailed information about companies and individuals and their relationships.
 - The Analysis Of Affiliated Persons And Final Beneficiaries. Information about relationships between companies and individuals being their owners and
 leaders, or having indirect coupling as relatives, purchasing participants or as persons related to other associated companies. Illustrative multi-tiered
 analysis of the property and corporate management structure, automated search of relationships and their graphical schemes construction, export of the
 schemes into various formats and publication.
 - Commenting System. Notes to companies analytics reports, comments tagging, file attaching and comments administration. Commentary widget can be
 placed on any page of the site.



These products attracted new clients and doubled National Credit Bureau volume of sales.

I promoted some of my ideas and product functionality proposals, managed the development and product release.

Developed the service of receiving information about companies and individuals from the internet resources.

Designed and developed UI and frontend of the Unisearch.

Designed and developed UI and frontend of the The Analysis Of Affiliated Persons And Final Beneficiaries and developed the export of cloud diagram into PNG. PDF. DOCX.

Designed and developed UI and frontend of the Commenting System.

Created the presentation of "The Analysis Of Affiliated Persons And Final Beneficiaries" for the conference held by National Credit Bureau.

Technologies: JavaScript, AngularJS, RequireJS, jQuery, Lodash, Raphaël, jsPlumb, Backbone.js, HTML, CSS, LESS, Bootstrap, HTTP, REST, Node.js, Express, PhantomJS, Grunt, Java, Spring Framework, iText, docx4j, Freemarker, Apache Solr, Apache Tomcat, MongoDB, Neo4j, Adobe Photoshop.

* Payment-related solutions for Runet Business Systems: Integration processing, payment gateways and online payment systems, Mobile banking USSD payment application, Mobile banking application REST API design, Social network application for mobile account deposit.

Technologies: Java, XML, HTTP, Web Services, SOAP, USSD, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS.

* Convergent Billing System for video monitoring system belonging to Ivideon company.

I designed and developed API.

Technologies: HTTP, REST, Python, PostgreSQL.

* Furniture online store 2×2 Mebel

I developed frontend.

Technologies: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, REST, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS.

* Designed and developed i18n-packages for localization. These packages are used for localization of frontend and backend of software solutions.

Technologies: gettext, Node.js, Grunt, RequireJS, JavaScript, Java.

* Designed and developed web application build helper.

Technologies: Node.js, Grunt, RequireJS, JavaScript.

Java Developer

BPC Banking Technologies

January 2011 - January 2013

Group of companies. Moscow, Russia. bpcbt.com

Integrated Aeroflot ticket booking system with Sberbank payment gate.

Designed and developed Fraud Control – system of fraud probability determination, based on the payment data and rules of fraud probability determination. This system was implemented in Sberbank и Alfabank.

Technologies: Java, SQL, XML, HTTP, Web Services, SOAP, Spring, Spring Security, iBatis, Hibernate, Mozilla Rhino, Jetty, Oracle Database, PostgreSQL, VAADIN, Freemarker.

Frontend / Backend Developer, Cofounder

Bildika

B2C e-commerce startup. Moscow. Russia. bildika.ru

January 2010 - January 2011

Organized startup from idea to product launch, designed and developed e-commerce system "Construction And Repair Goods Market Aimed On Customer Convenience".



Technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Java, Spring, Spring Security, JSP, JSTL, Apache Tiles, iBatis, PostgreSQL, Apache Lucene, Apache Tomcat, SQL, XML.

Lead Developer, Deputy Director INT Projects

May 2004 - January 2010

Outsourcing company. Moscow, Russia.

Designed and developed software. Analysed business requirements and developed worked out specifications. Formed a software development team, held technical interviews. Led software development team, consisting of 2-5 members.

- $\ensuremath{\ast}$ Designed and developed UI and frontend of the following projects:
 - · Crude oil mining monitoring web application
 - Web based document management system
 - · Web based system of the distance education
 - Automated system of decision system support in transport logistics

Technologies: JavaScript, ExtJS, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Prof-UIS, C++, Win32 API, GIS.



* Designed and developed SDK for coding-decoding of bi-dimensional barcode PDF417. SDK for recognition of machine-readable passport-visa documents for "The State System of Production, Execution, And Control Of Passport-Visa Documents Of New Generation".



* Designed and developed Reporting System for "The State System of Production, Execution, And Control Of Passport-Visa Documents Of New



Technologies: Java, XML, XSL-T, XSL-FO, Apache FOP, JFreeChart.

Research Scientist

Generation".

Scientific-research Department of Moscow State Industrial University

May 2003 - October 2005

University. Moscow, Russia. mospolytech.ru

Was engaged in scientific research, wrote scientific-research articles and reports.

Developed firmware for the roughness automated measurement and parameter estimation, based on the three-dimensional analysis of the surface.

Got the patent #2004612670 "Program Control Of A Surface Analyzer".

Technologies: Java, C/C++, Electronics, Mechatronics, Signal processing, Fourier and wavelet transform.

Software Developer

Metrostroy, Moscow Joint-Stock Company "Likhachov Plant", Almazavtomatika

1996 - 2005

Developed estimate-analytical software for the internal use in a building organization.

Developed control and visualization UI of diamond cassette dispensing information system.

Developed programming and software technology skills.

Technologies: Assembler x86, C/C++.

Education

Postgraduate specialization course "Automation of technological processes" of Moscow State Industrial University, 2003-2006

Applied mathematics and physics department of Moscow State Industrial University, 1995-2001

Engineer's degree, Automation of technological processes.

Code & Projects

Public

github.com/newpointer/autokad github.com/newpointer/i18n-bin aithub.com/newpointer/i18n-is github.com/newpointer/i18n-java github.com/newpointer/web-bin github.com/newpointer/web-app github.com/newpointer/commons-js github.com/newpointer/webrender github.com/creditnet/connections_landing

Private

github.com/ankostyuk/demo-rsearch github.com/ankostyuk/demo-connections-ui github.com/ankostvuk/demo-extraneous github.com/ankostyuk/demo-relation-ui github.com/ankostyuk/demo-relations github.com/ankostyuk/demo-creditnet-comments github.com/ankostyuk/demo-storefront

